Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings AIA.031.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Private Performances, 1970-1992, circa 1970-Jan 27, 1992
  - Mulcahy Family and Mick. aiamm8DAT, undated; aiamm8DAT (Box 76, Box 69)
  - Mulcahy Family: Mick (accordion), Louise (flute, uilleann pipes), Michelle (fiddle, harp) Labeled "#2." aiamm734C, Oct 11, 1982; aiamm734C (Box 27, Box 46)
  - Mulcahy Family: Mick (accordion), Louise (flute, uilleann pipes), Michelle (fiddle, harp). Labeled "Banjo Tunes." Rough studio mixes counted off by Mick Mulcahy (accordion) followed by one commercial track by an unidentified performer. (Length: 00:15:00) aiamm737C, undated; aiamm737C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulcahy Family: Mick (accordion), Louise (flute, uilleann pipes), Michelle (fiddle, harp). Labeled "One Tune." aiamm739C, undated; aiamm739C (Box 27, Box 46)
  - Mulcahy Family: Mick (accordion), Louise (flute, uilleann pipes), Michelle (fiddle, harp). Labeled "Sample Tunes for CD - Shanachie Records." (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm738C, undated; aiamm738C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulcahy Family: Mick (accordion), Louise (flute, uilleann pipes), Michelle (fiddle, harp). Labeled "Tunes for a CD." Demo tape of tunes introduced by Mick Mulcahy and sent to Moloney for projected recording. Includes some solo Mick Mulcahy performances. (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm736C, Nov 1, 1999; aiamm736C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulcahy Family: Mick (accordion), Louise (uilleann pipes, flute), Michelle (harp, fiddle). Interview for the notes to the Shanachie CD, The Mulcahy Family, produced by Mick Moloney. (Length: 00:25:00) aiamm735C, Feb 9, 1999; aiamm735C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulhaire, Martin (accordion, b. Eyrecourt, Co. Galway) Interview in Queens, NY. All Ireland accordion winner and noted composer Mulhaire discusses his personal and musical history. (One CD – Length: 00:38:56) aiamm137R, Dec 5, 1981; aiamm137R (Box 31, Box 10, Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mulhaire, Martin (accordion) Two studio mixes of Mulhaire, flute and piano, labeled "Mulhaire, Egan and Briley"; Egan, Seamus (flute, banjo) Rough mixes and multiple takes for Egan's LP Traditional Irish Music; O'Connell, Robbie (vocals, guitar) Private performance of songs. (Total length: 00:30:00) aiamm740C, circa 1985; aiamm740C (Box 46, Box 25, Item aiamm740C)
  - Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle, b. July 12, 1954, Northampton, England) Interview in New Canaan, CT. Mulvihill, a member of the Irish Tradition and son of fiddler and teacher Martin Mulvihill, discusses his personal and musical history. (One CD – Length: 00:44:28) aiamm142R, Jul 31, 1978; aiamm142R (Box 3, Folder 18, Box 31, Box 10)
  - Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle) Interview by a woman named Erin. Topics include: background, musical style, Baroque influences, traditional influences and norms, holding fiddle, ceilis. (Length: 01:30:00) aiamm744C, Sep 4, 1981; aiamm744C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle) Labeled "Own Tunes." Private performance by Mulvihill followed by a session with unidentified accordion and pipes. (Total length: 00:15:00) aiamm745C, undated; aiamm745C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle) Labeled "Review Tape." Rough studio mixes with countoffs for the album The Flax in Bloom. (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm743C, circa 1979; aiamm743C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle), Long, Donna (piano) Private performance. (Length: 01:00:00) aiamm742C, Mar 3, 1977; aiamm742C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Copy of master mixes, with log, for the album, The Flax in Bloom. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm741C, 1974; aiamm741C (Box 46, Box 25)
  - Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar, banjo) Rough mixes, unaccompanied and with guitar and banjo.(Length: 00:45:00) aiamm746C, undated; aiamm746C (Box 25, Box 46)
  - Side A: Mulvihill, Brendan; Moloney, Mick; Side B: Celtic Thunder: Interview (Terry Winch, Linda Hickman, Steve Hickman, Anita Korn, Jesse Winch). aiamm1299C, undated; aiamm1299C (Box 68, Box 44)
  - Mulvihill, Charlie (accordion, b.1917, Bronx, NY, d. 1975), Unidentified (piano), Unidentified (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Middle Village, Queens, NY by Charlie Mulvihill for fiddler and composer Ed Reavy. (Two CDs – Total length: 02:00:49) aiamm36R, circa 1970; aiamm36R (Box 8, Box 3, Folder 19, Box 28)
  - Mulvihill, Charlie and Denis Murphy. aiamm1399C, undated; aiamm1399C (Box 70, Box 44)
  - Mulvihill, Charlie and Paddy O'Brien. aiamm1276C, undated; aiamm1276C (Box 44, Box 68)
  - Mulvihill, Martin aiamm1311C, undated; aiamm1311C (Box 44, Box 65)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle, b. 1923, Ballygoughin, Co. Limerick, d. July 21, 1987, Co. Limerick), Moloney, Mick (guitar, mandolin, banjo), Mulvihill, Dawn (piano) Private performance of traditional music and a short interview with Martin recorded in the Bronx, NY. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:37:29) aiamm84R, 85R, 86R, Mar 6, 1976; aiamm84R, aiamm85R, aiamm86R (Box 3, Folder 20, Box 9, Box 30)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle) aiamm751C, undated; aiamm751C (Box 46, Box 27)
  - Mulvihill, Martin: "The Humours of Glin" aiamm1277C, undated; aiamm1277C (Box 65, Box 44)
  - Mulvihill, Martin: "The Humours of Glin." aiamm1280C, undated; aiamm1280C (Box 68, Box 44)
  - Mulvihill, Martin: "The Humours of Glin." aiamm1347C, undated; aiamm1347C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Mulvihill, Martin: Interview. aiamm1298C, May 18, 1977; aiamm1298C (Box 65, Box 44)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle) Interview in the Bronx, NY. Mulvihill, fiddle player and founder of a large school of Irish music in New York in the 1970s, discusses tunes recorded by his students for an LP. (One CD – Length: 00:07:11) aiamm131R, Dec 16, 1979; aiamm131R (Box 3, Folder 21, Box 9, Box 31)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle) Private performance followed by session at Jack Coen's house, Bronx, NY featuring Sean McGlynn (accordion), Mike Flynn (flute, b. Sligo), Fr.Charlie Coen (concertina). (15 minutes); interviews with Fr. Charlie Coen, McGlynn and Flynn about their lives and music. (Total length:00:30:00) aiamm748C, Mar 7, 1976; aiamm748C (Box 46, Box 25)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle), Mulvihill, Gail (banjo), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Three mixes for the album, Living Tradition. (Length:00:10:00) aiamm750C, circa 1979; aiamm750C (Box 46, Box 25)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (mandolin and guitar) and Mulvihill's students. Interview and private performance recorded in the Bronx, NY. Mulvihill's students discuss their interest and involvement with Irish music interspersed with eight minutes of traditional music performed by Mulvihill and Moloney. Students interviewed are: Carmel Glendon, Elizabeth Moran, Maureen Roche, Bernadette Lucy, Eileen Ivers, Michael Carolan, Patricia Conway, Dawn Mulvihill, Margie Mulvihill, Theresa Fitzpatrick, Philip Lane, Maureen O'Hara and Seamus Burke. (One CD – Length: 00:57:34) aiamm12R, Apr 30, 1977; aiamm12R (Box 8, Box 28, Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Labeled "Lough Sheelin's Shore." aiamm423R, undated; aiamm423R (Box 46, Box 17)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Studio mixes for the LP Traditional Irish Fiddling from County Limerick. Labeled "Friday - Tape 10." (Length: 01:00:00) aiamm422R, circa 1977; aiamm422R (Box 14, Box 46)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Private performance. (Length: 00:55:00) aiamm747C, Mar 6, 1976; aiamm747C (Box 46, Box 25)
  - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (mandolin, long-knecked mandolin, guitar), Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle), Mulvihill, Charlie (accordion) Private performances by Martin Mulvihill and Moloney of tune versions (Oct 25, 1978); private performances by Brendan Mulvihill and Moloney of tune versions and Mulvihill's compositions followed by interview discussing composition and music (Nov 11, 1979); private performances by Charlie Mulvihill and unidentified fiddle and piano (Nov 26, 1979). (Total length: 00:45:00) aiamm749C, Oct 25, 1978, Nov 11, 1979, and Nov 26, 1979; aiamm749C (Box 46, Box 25)
  - Mulvihill, Martin, Band Practice. Bronx, NY. Rehearsal of traditional music recorded in the Bronx, NY. (One CD – Length: 00:30:10) aiamm158, Feb 17, 1977; aiamm158 (Box 3, Folder 23, Box 10)
  - Mulvihill, Martin, Ceili Bands (folder one). Recording session in Connecticut for the Green Linnet recording, Irish Music, the Living Tradition (1009). The Glinside, Eire-Og and Glincastle Ceili Bands. Eileen Ivers (fiddle), Patricia Conway (accordion), Pat Burke (accordion) Gail Mulvihill (banjo), Martin Mulvihill (fiddle) Mick Moloney (guitar) and Unidentified (piano) play solos, duets and trios. (Four CDs – Total length: 02:11:58) aiamm322R, 323R, 1977; aiamm322R, aiamm323R (Box 3, Folder 24, Box 12, Box 33)
  - Mulvihill, Martin, Ceili Bands (folder two). Recording session in Connecticut for the Green Linnet recording, Irish Music, the Living Tradition (1009). Eileen Ivers (fiddle), Gail Mulvihill (banjo), Martin Mulvihill (fiddle) Mick Moloney (guitar) play in various combinations. (One CD – Length: 00:46:55) aiamm324R, 1977; aiamm324R (Box 12, Box 33, Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Mulvihill Ceili Band: Interview in New Canaan, CT. aiamm1269C, Jan 27, 1979; aiamm1269C (Box 44, Box 67)
  - Mulvihill Ceili Bands. Labeled "Patricia Conway, E. Ivers, Eire Oge and Glenside Ceili Bands, Acc Trio, Pat Burke (Piano Acc.), Gail Mulvihill." aiamm753C, undated; aiamm753C (Box 56, Box 27)
  - Mulvihill Ceili Bands. Studio mixes for the album, Living Tradition, including solos and small groups. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm752C, Dec 4, 1979; aiamm752C (Box 46, Box 25)
  - Mulvihill Family. aiamm754C, undated; aiamm754C (Box 46, Box 27)
  - Mulvihill's, Martin, School of Irish Music, Bronx, NY. Private performance of traditional music recorded in the Bronx, NY. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:56:25) aiamm159C, Feb 19, 1977; aiamm159C (Box 34, Box 10, Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Mulvihill School. 24-track Eastside Sound master tape for the LP, Living Tradition, featuring Gail Mulvihill (banjo) and small groups, with track sheet. aiamm424R, undated; aiamm424R (Box 22, Box 56)
  - Natan, Ehud (flute, mandolin) Private performance by Tel Aviv musician. (Length: 00:05:00) aiamm755C, undated; aiamm755C (Box 46, Box 25)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano, b. 1915, Chicago, IL, d. 1993) Recording session in Chicago, IL. Innovative for her melody playing on the piano, Kane is joined by Johnny McGreevy (fiddle) for a few selections. (One CD – Length: 00:20:58) aiamm143R, May 2, 1980; aiamm143R (Box 3, Folder 27, Box 31, Box 10)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano). aiamm1241C, undated; aiamm1241C (Box 67, Box 44)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano). aiamm1349C, undated; aiamm1349C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Labeled "E.K.N. 12 tracks of piano, Selections by Sean McGuire, Patsy Cawley and E.K. Grand Spy - piano." aiamm425R, Jul 25, 1956; aiamm425R (Box 46, Box 17)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano): Labeled "Piano Selections." aiamm1319C, undated; aiamm1319C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Recording session in Chicago, IL. (Four CDs – Total length: 01:43:15) aiamm145R, 146R, 147R, 148R, May 3, 1980; aiamm145R, aiamm146R, aiamm147R, aiamm148R (Box 31, Box 10, Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Recording session in Chicago, IL. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:50:53) aiamm149R, 150R, May 5, 1980; aiamm149R, aiamm150R (Box 31, Box 10, Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Recording session labeled "Tape 3" featuring Johnny Harling (tin whistle), Frank Burke (fiddle), Jimmy Neary (whistle), Johnny McGreevy and Liz Carroll (fiddles). aiamm426R, undated; aiamm426R (Box 46, Box 17)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Interview. Kane discusses the tunes she recorded on May 5, 1980 in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:03:17) aiamm150R, aiamm150R (Box 31, Box 10, Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Recording session in Chicago, IL. Kane is joined by Johnny McGreevy (fiddle) for several selections. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:27:38) aiamm62R, 63R, 64R, Aug 15, 1982; aiamm62R, aiamm63R, aiamm64R (Box 3, Folder 31, Box 9, Box 29)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) and Unidentified Musicians. A compilation of recordings of traditional music. The original tape belonged to fiddler and composer Ed Reavy. (Two CDs – Total length: 02:12:28) aiamm27R, Oct, 1977; aiamm27R (Box 3, Folder 32, Box 28, Box 8)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) Recording session in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:25:40) aiamm144R, May 2, 1980; aiamm144R (Box 3, Folder 33, Box 10, Box 31)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) Interview in Chicago, IL. Kane and McGreevy discuss the tunes they recorded on Aug 15, 1982. (One CD – Length: 00:05:02) aiamm64R, aiamm64R (Box 3, Folder 34, Box 9, Box 29)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle), Carroll, Liz (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:06:50) aiamm144R, May 2, 1980; aiamm144R (Box 3, Folder 35, Box 10, Box 31)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), Moloney, Mick (mandolin) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:05:43) aiamm150R, May 5, 1980; aiamm150R (Box 3, Folder 36, Box 10, Box 31)
  - Neary, Eleanor Kane; Anne Cully; and Frank O'Higgins. aiamm1265C, undated; aiamm1265C (Box 68, Box 44)
  - Nelson, Barry (folder one) (vocals, guitar, mandolin, whistle, b. May, 1944, Belfast, Co. Antrim) Interview recorded at McGurk's Irish Pub, St. Louis, MO. Nelson discusses his personal and musical history. (Four CDs – Total length: 02:05:11) aiamm231C, 232C, Jun 19, 1984; aiamm231C, aiamm232C (Box 4, Folder 1, Box 11, Box 34)
  - Nelson, Barry (folder two) (vocals, guitar, mandolin, whistle, b. May, 1944, Belfast, Co. Antrim) Interview recorded at McGurk's Irish Pub, St. Louis, MO. Nelson discusses the Irish bar circuit in the U.S. (One CD – Length: 00:32:05) aiamm233C, Jun 19, 1984; aiamm233C (Box 4, Folder 2, Box 11, Box 34)
  - Newton, Wendy (Green Linnet Records) interview. aiamm1242C, Apr 5, 1994; aiamm1242C (Box 44, Box 68)
  - Nugent, Larry (whistle) aiamm758C, undated; aiamm758C (Box 27, Box 47)
  - Nugent, Larry (flute) Interview. aiamm756C, Sep 29, 1991; aiamm756C (Box 47, Box 27)
  - Nugent, Larry (flute, whistle), Unidentified (piano) Demo for Moloney produced recording. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm757C, undated; aiamm757C (Box 25, Box 47)
  - O'Beirne, Lad aiamm1290C, undated; aiamm1290C (Box 65, Box 44)
  - O'Brien, Andy (guitar and vocals, b. Co. Kerry), McComiskey, Billy (accordion, b. Brooklyn, NY) Interview in New Canaan, CT. Members of The Irish Tradition, O'Brien and McComiskey discuss their personal and musical histories and selections they recorded for the 1978 Green Linnet LP, The Corner House. (One CD – Length: 00:15:10) aiamm142R, Jul 29, 1978; aiamm142R (Box 4, Folder 3, Box 10, Box 31)
  - O'Brien, Andy (guitar, vocals) Private performance of one song, "Windmills." (Length: 00:10:00). aiamm427R, undated; aiamm427R (Box 14, Box 37)
  - O'Brien, Paddy (accordion, b. 1945, Daingean, Co. Offaly), Flynn, Mike (vocals, b. Co. Clare), Moloney, Mick (banjo). Private performance of traditional music recorded in Philadelphia, PA. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:28:15) aiamm235C, May 23, 1979; aiamm235C (Box 34, Box 11, Box 4, Folder 4)
  - O'Brien, Paddy (accordion) aiamm761C, undated; aiamm761C (Box 56, Box 27)
  - O'Brien, Paddy (accordion) Private performance at Moloney's house including some discussion of tunes. (Length: 00:35:00). aiamm759C, Jun 18, 1974; aiamm759C (Box 25, Box 37)
  - O'Brien, Paddy (accordion), Ryan, Sean (fiddle), Grant, Katherine Brennan (piano) Private session with small audience; Mulvihill, Charlie (accordion), Murphy, Dennis (fiddle), Grant, Katherine Brennan (piano) Recording session. (Length: 01:00:00) aiamm760C, undated; aiamm760C (Box 25, Box 47)
  - O'Byrne Dewitt, Justus (entrepreneur) Part one of interview recorded in Dedham, MA, March 3, 1977; aiamm1237C (Box 25, Audiocassette aiamm1237C, Box 42, Cd aiamm1237C)
    The owner of Copley Records talks about his music store and music in Boston from the 1930s to the 1970s
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 61 minutes.
  - O'Byrne Dewitt, Justus (entrepreneur) Part two of interview recorded in Dedham, MA, March 3, 1977; aiamm762C (Box 25, Audiocassette aiamm762C, Box 37, Cd aiamm762C)
    The owner of Copley Records talks about his music store and music in Boston from the 1930s to the 1970s. (Length: 01:30:00)
    Duration: 57 minutes.
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Interview recorded in New York, NY. Piper, organizer and teacher Ochs discusses his personal and musical history. Topics include: non-Irish playing Irish music, piping, the Irish Arts Center. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:44:38) aiamm237, 238, Feb 24, 1978; aiamm237, aiamm238 (Box 11, Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes) Labeled "Ochs Tape 1 - Copy of Bill Ochs' Tape on Old Uilleann Pipes Recordings." aiamm428R, Dec 1, 1977; aiamm428R (Box 47, Box 17)
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes) Labeled "Ochs Tape 2." Recording session featuring Bill Ochs (uilleann pipes) and unidentified fiddle and concertina. aiamm429R, Dec 1, 1977; aiamm429R (Box 17, Box 47)
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes) Recording session labeled "Takes 6.7.8." aiamm431R, Apr 11, 1980; aiamm431R (Box 17, Box 56)
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes) Recording session labeled "Tracks 1,2,3,4,5,9 & 10" with log. aiamm430R, Apr 11, 1980; aiamm430R (Box 56, Box 24)
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length:00:27:53) aiamm250, Apr 3, 1978; aiamm250 (Box 11, Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Recording session and interview in Philadelphia, PA. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:19:34) aiamm251, Apr 4, 1978; aiamm251 (Box 11, Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. (Four CDs – Total length: 00:55:31) aiamm246, 247, 248, 249, Apr 17, 1980; aiamm246, aiamm247, aiamm248, aiamm249 (Box 11, Box 4, Folder 8)
  - O'Connell, Robbie: Six Songs. aiamm1392C, undated; aiamm1392C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - O'Connell, Robbie (vocals, guitar) Labeled "Final Mixes - Love of the Land." aiamm767C, undated; aiamm767C (Box 27, Box 47)
  - O'Connell, Robbie (vocals, guitar) Labeled "Tape for Mick." Demo versions of four O'Connell compositions (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm765C, undated; aiamm765C (Box 47, Box 25)
  - O'Connell, Robbie (vocals, guitar) Private performance of "House of Cards" with handwritten note reading "brand new song for Mick." (Length: 00:10:00) aiamm764C, 1996; aiamm764C (Box 47, Box 25)
  - O'Connell, Robbie; Harte, Frank. aiamm1445C, undated; aiamm1445C (Box 44, Box 70)
  - O'Connell, Robbie (vocals, guitar), O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Unidentified (accordions) Private performances followed by private session with unidentified accordion, guitar and banjo. (Length: 01:30:00) aiamm766C, undated; aiamm766C (Box 25, Box 47)
  - O'Connell, Robbie (vocals, guitar), Moloney, Mick (vocals, guitar, banjo), Keane, Jimmy (accordion) Labeled "Songs Final Mix – Stick to the Crathur." Nearly final studio mixes for the album, There Were Roses. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm763C, circa 1986; aiamm763C (Box 25, Box 47)
  - O'Connor, Gerry (tracks 1-15); Caoimhin Valley (tracks 16-18). aiamm16CD, undated; aiamm16CD (Box 76, Box 74)
  - O'Connor, Mick (banjo), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Private informal tunes in Limerick (15 minutes) taped over large session in Milltown Malbay, Co. Clare (5 minutes). (Total length: 00:20:00). aiamm768C, Jul 10, 1984; aiamm768C (Box 37, Box 25)
  - O'Donnell, Eoin and Sean. Interview with two small children telling jokes and stories. (Length: 00:40:00) aiamm769C, Aug 31, 1974; aiamm769C (Box 25, Box 47)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) 16-track Morning Star Studios master tape including the "Foggy Dew" and "Planxty Irwin." aiamm434R, 1982; aiamm434R (Box 22, Box 56)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle, b. 1932, Co. Derry), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length: 00:14:01) aiamm319R, Feb 8, 1977; aiamm319R (Box 12, Box 4, Folder 9, Box 33)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Interview at Moloney's home on W. Harvey St., Phialdelphia, PA after a gig. O'Donnell discusses the Four Provinces Band, Eddie Lee in the late 1950s and compositions for a proposed book. (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm771C, Sep 10, 1991; aiamm771C (Box 25, Box 47)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Interview in Bethlehem, PA (15 minutes, Feb 12, 1978); interview with Dan and Tina Verbo, directors of 1979 Philadelphia Ceili Group Festival and Sally Dougherty, member of the Ceili Group (15 minutes, Dec 3, 1978). (Total length: 00:30:00) aiamm770C, Feb 12 and Dec 3, 1978; aiamm770C (Box 47, Box 25)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. for the 1991 release, The Music of Ed Reavy. (One CD – Length: 00:05:56) aiamm320R, May 24, 1977; aiamm320R (Box 33, Box 12, Box 4, Folder 10)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in [Philadelphia, PA] for the 1978 Green Linnet release, Slow Airs and Set Dances. (One CD – Length: 00:28:51) aiamm325R, Feb 11, 1978; aiamm325R (Box 33, Box 4, Folder 11, Box 13)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in [Philadelphia, PA] for the 1978 Green Linnet release, Slow Airs and Set Dances. (One CD – Length: 00:26:26) aiamm327R, Mar 26, 1978; aiamm327R (Box 4, Folder 12, Box 13, Box 33)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (mandolin, guitar) Private performance of traditional music recorded in [Philadelphia, PA?] (One CD – Length: 00:08:54) aiamm218C, Jun 10, 1979; aiamm218C (Box 4, Folder 13, Box 11, Box 34)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Recording session labeled "8." (Length 00:45:00) aiamm433R, Apr 16, 1978; aiamm433R (Box 47, Box 15)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Recording session of set dances and slow airs labeled "Tape 5." (Length 01:00:00) aiamm432R, Mar 25, 1978; aiamm432R (Box 15, Box 47)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Labeled "Tape I: 1 of 2." aiamm435R, undated; aiamm435R (Box 47, Box 17)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Labeled "Copy 2 of 2." aiamm436R, undated; aiamm436R (Box 17, Box 47)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Private unaccompanied performance. (Length: 00:05:00) aiamm772C, undated; aiamm772C (Box 47, Box 25)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Philadelphia, PA (One CD – Length: 00:09:47) aiamm220C, Jan 31, 1980; aiamm220C (Box 34, Box 11, Box 4, Folder 14)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Private performance in Philadelphia, PA. O'Donnell plays his own compositions. (One CD – Length: 00:05:07) aiamm316C, undated; aiamm316C (Box 34, Box 4, Folder 15, Box 12)
  - O'Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music, including original compositions, recorded in Philadelphia, PA (One CD – Length: 00:16:06) aiamm317C, undated; aiamm317C (Box 4, Folder 16, Box 34, Box 12)
  - O'Donnell, Josie aiamm1312C, undated; aiamm1312C (Box 44, Box 65)
  - O'Hare, Kieran; Harte, Frank; Mulcahy's. aiamm1289C, undated; aiamm1289C (Box 69, Box 44)
  - O'Leary, Eamon; Ourceau, Patrick: Interview by Mick Moloney at Ireland House. aiamm1CD, Apr 17, 2003; aiamm1CD (Box 76, Box 74)
  - O'Reilly, Mary (organizer) Interview in Chicago with Clare native O'Reilly, organizer of the Irish component of Chicago's International Folk Festival, as part of the Chicago Ethnic Arts Project. (Length: 01:00:00) Original tapes are at the American Folklife Center. aiamm773C, May 4, 1977; aiamm773C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm773C, Box 37)